A Guide to the Papers of Michael D'Orso
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Michael D'Orso 1993-1995
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
MG 67
6.25 linear feet, 13 Hollinger document cases, 2 cassette boxes
Administrative Information
Access
Open to researchers without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Michael D'Orso, April 22, 1999
Biographical/Historical Information
Mike D'Orso earned both his undergraduate degree in philosophy and his master's degree in English from the College of William and Mary. He taught high school English and has been a staff writer for Commonwealth magazine. As a writer for the Virginian-Pilot Newspaper he won numerous national honors including the Penney-Missouri Prize for general feature writing and three Pulitzer Prize nominations.
D'Orso's work has also appeared in publications such as Sports Illustrated, Fortune, Reader's Digest and People magazine. Additionally he has written a chapter on journalism research methods for The Complete Book of Feature Writing; and his writing on author Jack Kerouac has been included in both Studies in American Fiction and the QPB Literary Review.
Mike D'Orso has also written 13 non-fiction books (see Bibliography). Included among those works is Like Judgment Day: The Ruin and Redemption of a Town Called Rosewood, which was a New York Times best- seller, and American Library Association Notable Book of the Year, and winner of the Lillian Smith Book Award for writing on the subject of social justice. The Papers of Mike D'Orso housed in the Old Dominion University Special Collections consists of his notes, interview transcripts, research done while writing Like Judgement Day.
Scope and Content Information
The Mike D'Orso - Rosewood papers date from 1993-1995. Included in this collection are interview tapes and transcripts, photographs, newspaper clippings, and other materials collected while writing the book. Also included are edited sections of the manuscript and galley proofs.
The collection is arranged info five sections. Series I, interviewees and characters, includes photographs, interview transcripts and notes on individuals interviewed for the book and on historical characters in the story. Series II, background research, includes newspaper clippings, book chapters and articles used as background research for the book. Series III, legal/legislative papers, contains an insurance valuation report used to determine compensation and the transcript of the Florida state legislative hearing on the Rosewood claims bill. Series IV, editing of manuscript, includes photographs used in the book, edited manuscript and galley proofs. Series V includes audio cassette tapes, video tapes and computer disks.
BIBLIOGRAPHY - MICHAEL D'ORSO
Bibliography
Seeds of Hope: A Physician's Personal Triumph Over
In Praise of Public Life, with Joseph Lieberman, Simon & Schuster, 2000
Winning with Integrity: Getting What You're Worth Without Selling Your Soul, with Leigh Steinberg, Times Books, 1999
Seeds of Hope: A Physician's Personal Ttriumph Over
Seeds of Hope: A Physician's Personal Ttriumph Over
Body-for- Life: 12 Weeks to Mental and Physical Strength, with Bill Phillips, HarperCollins Publishers, 1999
Somerset Homecoming: Recovering a Lost Heritage, with Dorothy Spruill Redford, University of North Carolina Press, 1998
Walking with the Wind: A Memoir of the Movement, with John Lewis, Harcourt Brace, 1998
Thin is Just a Four-letter Word: Living Fit-- for All Shapes and Sizes, with Dee Hakala, Dell, 1997
Like Judgment Day: The Ruin and Redemption of a Town Called Rosewood, Boulevard Books, 1996
Pumping Granite: And Other Portraits of People at Play, Texas Tech University Press, 1994
Rise and Walk: The Trial and Triumph of Dennis Byrd, with Dennis Byrd, HarperCollins, 1993
For the Children: Lessons from a Visionary Principal, with Madeline Cartwright, Doubleday, 1993
The Cost of Courage: The Journey of an American Congressman, with Carl Eliott, Doubleday, 1992
Fast Takes: Slices of Life Through a Journalist's Eye, Hampton Roads Publishing Co., 1990
Contents List
- Series I: Interviewees and Characters
  - Wilson Hall (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Willie Evans (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Margie Hall Johnson (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Katherine Hall (Sam Hall's grandaughter) (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lonnie Carroll (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Michael O'McCarthy (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Robie Mortin (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Arnett Goins (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mary Hall Daniels (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lee Ruth Bradley (Davis) (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minnie Lee Langley (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Vera Hamilton (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Dorothy Hosey (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Rosewood Committee/ "Family" (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Lillie Washington (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Eva Jenkins (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Janie Bradley Black (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Annette Shakir (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Mae McDonald (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Gretchen Douglas (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Rosetta Bradley Jackson (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Gary Moore - AG Correspondence (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Gary Moore I (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Gary Moore II (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Gary Moore Stories from "Tallahassee Democrat" (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Joel Bernstein (reporter) (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Ed Bradley (reporter) (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Ella Fitzegerald (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Mudcat" Grant (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Christopher Wilson (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Carolyn Tucker (Vita only) (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Randolph Hodges (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 19)
  - John Rutledge (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Doyal and Fuji Scoggins (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Wesley & Christy Thompson (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Leonard & Mary Reynolds (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Collins & Jessy Taylor "Old Cuz" & Hatcher (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Judy Chapman (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Pete Gallagher (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Mike "Salty" Reftis (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Steve Hanlon I (Lawyer) (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Steve Hanlon II (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Martha Barnett (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Manny Dobrinsky (Lawyer) (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Jim Peters (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Holland & Chesterfield Smith (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 3)
  - David Colburn (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Larry Rivers (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Elmer Jonhson (White survivor) (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cary Hardee (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Ernest Parham (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Maxine Jones (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Tom Dye (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Bill Rogers (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Hanlon interview of Richard Hixson (Box-folder Box 3,Folder 12)
  - Mike (Miguel) De Granby (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Richard Hixson (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 14)
  - "Hixson Summary" and "Moore to Hixson" (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Al Lawson/Charlie Williams (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 16)
  - John Long (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Bill Posey (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Elaine Gordon (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 19)
  - "Bo" Johnson (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Charlie Williams (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Pete Antonacci (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Dave Thomas (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Robert Trammell (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Thelma Hawkins (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Berthina Fagin (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Lillie Mae Washington (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Eva Robinson Walker (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Ivory Fuller (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Ernest Blocker (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Sarah Woodard Logan (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Lucille Wimbush (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 32)
  - George Davis (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Estrella Sara Daily (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Sarah Lexie Jane Goins Ward (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Theresa Brown Robinson (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Family Trees & Characters (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Photos I (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Photos II (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Photos III (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Photos IV (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Wallace Jordan death certificate (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Arnett Doctor Interview (descendants) (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Arnett Doctor Interview & Notes I (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Arnett Doctor Interviews & Notes II (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Arnett Documents (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Rosewood Phone numbers & addresses (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Martha Pillsbury (Walter & Carolyn) (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Yvonne Doctor (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Rosewood Interviews: Tape 1 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Rosewood Interviews: Tape 2 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Rosewood Interviews: Tape 3 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Rosewood Interviews: Tape 4 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Rosewood Interviews: Tape 5 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Rosewood Interviews: Tape 6 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Rosewood Interviews: Tape 7 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Rosewood Interviews: Tape 8 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Rosewood Interviews: Tape 9 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Rosewood Interviws: Tape 10 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Rosewood Interviews: Tape 11 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Rosewood Interviews: Tape 12 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Rosewood Interviews: Tape 13 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Rosewood Interviews: Tape 14 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Rosewood Interviews: Tape 15 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Rosewood Interviews: Tape 16 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Rosewood Interviews: Tape 17 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 11)
- Series II: Background Research
  - James Eaton (FAMU Black Archives) (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 12)
  - "Black Man Killings" newspaper clipping Virginian Pilot (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 13)
  - "Monkey" Story (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Kenneth Jones - Rosewood documentary (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Orlando Sentinel (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Tampa Tribune (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Tallahassee Democrat Clippings (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 18)
  - News Clippings (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Letters to Editors on Rosewood (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 20)
  - "Cracker: The history of a Southeastern ethnic, economic, and racial epithet" Names, March 1987 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 21)
  - "Attention White People" (Klan protests) (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Census & Prison Records (Archives) (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Old Newspaper Clippings (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 24)
  - 1923 News Clippings (Archives) (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 25)
  - 1923 Grand Jury (Long & DeCottes) (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Japanese Reparations Act (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Review of History Study (Florida State University) (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "Race, ethnicity and the politics of economic development: A case study of Cedar Key, Florida" (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Legal/Legislative Summary (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Hearing (News Clippings) (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Florida Legislature 1994 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Florida House Bill (News clippings) 1994 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 6)
  - "The Riddle of Dr. Mudd" (Samuel Mudd) Ch. 14 & notes (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 7)
  - House Debate, April 4, 1994 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Florida Senate (News Clipppings) (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Governor signing bill (News Clippings) (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 10)
  - "Florida legislature: 1994 Summary of General Legislation" (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 11)
  - St. Petersburg Police Department (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Attorney General's Office (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 13)
  - FDLE (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Business Cards (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Check List (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 16)
  - " A documented history of the incident which occured at Rosewood, Florida, in January 1923" (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Appendices to a documented history of the incident... (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Florida Maps (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Hilliard History and Statistics (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous writing, clipping re Hurricane Andrew, clipping re Klan killing (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Maps Florida counties, Rosewood 1923, Cedar Key (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 6)
  - City maps: Jacksonville-Duval county (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 7)
  - City maps: Greater Tampa (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 8)
  - City maps: Orlando (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Avis map of Florida (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Lynching Records and Statistics (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 11)
  - "Lynching Era" America (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Mark Twain (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Florida Lynchings (Ocoee & Perry, OK) (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Freemasons (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 15)
  - 1923 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Clippings Index (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Sanford History (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Lacoochee/Dade City I (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Lacoochee/Dade City II (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Lynching (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 22)
  - "Festival of Violence: An ananlysis of Southern Lynchings 1992-1930" (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 23)
  - "Racial Violence in the United States" Grimshaw (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 1)
  - U.S. History/Black History 1923 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "Race Riot at east St. Louis July 2, 1917" Rudwick (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "Rope and Faggot" Walter White (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "The anti-Lynching Movement 1883-1932" Grant (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "The Emergence of the New South 1913-1945" Tindall (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 6)
  - " The NAACP Crusade Against Lynching, 1909-1950" Zangrando (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 7)
  - "Lynching in the New South: Georgia and Virginia, 1880-1930" Brundage (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 8)
  - "Urban Racial Violence in the Twentieth Century" Boskin (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 9)
  - "To live and die in Dixie: A contribution to the Study of Southern violence" Reed (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 10)
  - "Race Riot: Chicago in the Red Summer of 1919" Tuttle (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper clippings: "Chain Gangs Return..." & "Wedowee" (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Wallace Terry (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Cedar Key and Levy County History I (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Cedar Key and Levy County History II (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 15)
- Series III: Legal/Legislative Papers
  - Insureance "Value" Report (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Goins and Langley. et al. Vs. State of Florida, Vol. 1 pages 1-125 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Goins and Langley. et al. Vs. State of Florida, Vol.2 pages 126-272 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Goins and Langley, et al. Vs. State of Florida, Vol.3 pages 273-355 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Goins and Langley, et al. Vs. State of Florida, Vol.4 pages 356-467 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Goins and Langley, et al. Vs. State of Florida, Vol.5 pages 468- 550 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Goins and Langley, et al. Vs. State of Florida, Vol.6 pages 551-611 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Goins and Langley, et al. Vs. State of Florida, Vol. 7 pages 612-743 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Goins and Langley, et al. Vs. State of Florida, Vol. 8 pages 744-786 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 9)
- Series IV: Editing of Manuscript
  - Photo Sources (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Sawmill group photo (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Rosewood photos (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Rosewood photos (Claims bill hearings) (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Rosewood photos (signing of claims bill) (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Chapter 1 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Chapter 2 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Chapter 3 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Chapter 3 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Chapter 6 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Chapter 7 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Chapter 8 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Chapter 9 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Chapter 10 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Chapter 11 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Chapter 12 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Chapter 13 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Chapter 15 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Chapter 16 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Chapter 17 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Chapter 18 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Chapter 19 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Chapter 21 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Chapter 22 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Chapter 23 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Chapter 24 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Chapter 25 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Chapter 26 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Chapter 27 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Chapter 28 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Chapter 29 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Chapter 30 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Chapter 31 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Chapter 32 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Chapter 33 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Chapter 34 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Chapter 35 Illustration (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Docnotes (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Rosewood photos part I (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Rosewood Photos Part II (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Rosewood Photos Part III (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Rosewood Photos Part IV (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 37)
  - "Like Judgement Day" Folder notes (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Photos - Minnie Lee Langley (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Maps - Florida, Levy County (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Book Photos (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Part I photos (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Part II photos (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Part III photos (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Part IV photos (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Part V photos (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Part VI photos (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Photos Needed (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Photos coming (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Photos received (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Florida State University Photos (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Gwendolyn Thompson (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Martha Barnett Photos (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Copies: "And God was all around us" title page, 1923 articles on Rosewood (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Florida Maps (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Song lyric permission (David Allan Coe) (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Photo Permissions (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Rosewood legal reading (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 58)
  - Rosewood Cover (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Tampa Tribune photos (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 60)
  - Willie Morris (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Palm Beach Post photos (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Hugh Scoggins (AP Tallahassee) (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 63)
  - Midge Laughlin (St. Petersburg Museum of History) (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 64)
  - Miami Herald Photos (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 65)
  - Florida State Archives (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Cedar Key Historical Photos (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Tallahassee Democrat photos (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Lynching Era photos (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Seminole Tribune Photos (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 5)
  - O'McCarthy photos (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Al Lawson photos (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Miguel De Granby (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Governor signing bill photo (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Ray Ansenault (author) "St. Petersburg and the Florida Dream 1888-1950 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Ernest Parham (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Brad Wasson (University of Florida photos) (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 12)
  - St. Petersburg Times (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Interview List (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Acknowlegments (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Like Judgement Day - title page, contents, prologue (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 16)
  - "Awakening" Part 1 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 17)
  - "The Survivors" Part 2 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 18)
  - "Movement" Part 3 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 19)
  - "The Claim" Part 4 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 20)
  - "Redemption" Part 5 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 21)
  - "Coming Home" Part 6 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Manuscript: And God was all around us: The story of the Rosewood Massacre by Mike D'orso (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Chapters 2 - 5 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Chapters 7 - 10 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Chapters 12 - 15 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Chapters 16, 17, 19, 20 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Chapters 21 - 24 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Chapters 26 - 29 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Chapters 30 - 33 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Acknowledgements (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence with Susan Raihoffer (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Chapters 7 & 10 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Title page, contents, prologue, part I (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Part 2 - The Survivors (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Part 3 - Movement (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Part 4 - The Claim (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Chapters 20 - 22 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Chapter 23 - 25 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Chapter 26 - 28 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Chapter 29 - 31 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Chapter 32 - 34 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Chapter 35 - 37 & Epilogue (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Part 5 - Redemption (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Part 6 - Coming Home (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Acknowledgement, Notes & Sources (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Prologue, Chapters 1 & 2 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Chapters 3, 4, 5 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Chapters 6, 8, 9 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Chapters 11-13 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Chapters 14 - 16 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Chapters 17 - 19 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 14)
- Series V: Audio, Video, Computer disks
  - Micro-cassettes numbered 1-45, interviews (Box Box 14)
  - Standard audio cassettes numbered 1- 8 (Box Box 14)
  - 2 audio cassettes labeled House Floor Debate 4/4/94 numbers 3 and 4 of 7 (Box Box 14)
  - VHS tape - "Redemption: The Rosewood Legacy" University of Florida News and Public Affairs (Box Box 14)
  - VHS tape - "Dateline NBC, Rosewood, 3/22/94" (Box Box 14)
  - VHS tape - "Rosewood Massacre" (Box Box 15)
  - VHS tape - "Povich - Rosewood" (Box Box 15)
  - 5" floppy disk - "Doc 6-8" (Box Box 15)
  - 5" floppy disk - "Doctor tape 8 - 11" (Box Box 15)
  - 5" floppy disk - "Doctor - tape 12-17" (Box Box 15)